<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Exit Status One</title>
    <description>A compilation of information about myself, technology, my projects, and a way to contact me.</description>
    <link>http://exitstatusone.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://exitstatusone.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Sun, 03 Jul 2016 13:24:32 -0600</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 03 Jul 2016 13:24:32 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.1.6</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Slackware 14.2 released</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The long awaited release of Slackware Linux 14.2 is finally here.  I
know I am a bit late with my post.  I have been very busy updating my
systems at home and for clients.  This includes my 2 Raspberry Pi&#39;s, old
Dell Inspiron laptop, My ZaReason Stratta 7440, and several virtual
private servers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everything is extremely stable.  I guess I forgot what it meant to run a
stable system due to the fact that the last couple years I was either
tracking Debian Sid/Unstable or Slackware -current (Slackware
development branch).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You are missing out if you are not running Slackware on at least one of
your systems!  Slackware provides a systemd free environment, stable
software, and empowers the user to take advantage of complete control of
the operating system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The ChangeLog.txt for Slackware 14.2...&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Thu Jun 30 20:26:57 UTC 2016
Slackware 14.2 x86_64 stable is released!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The long development cycle (the Linux community has lately been living
in &quot;interesting times&quot;, as they say) is finally behind us, and we&#39;re
proud to announce the release of Slackware 14.2.  The new release
brings many updates and modern tools, has switched from udev and eudev
(no systemd), and adds well over a hundred new packages to the system.
Thanks to the team, the upstream developers, the dedicated Slackware
community, and everyone else who pitched in to help make this release
a reality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The ISOs are off to be replicated, a 6 CD-ROM 32-bit set and a
dual-sided 32-bit/64-bit x86/x86_64 DVD.  Please consider supporting
the Slackware project by picking up a copy from store.slackware.com.
We&#39;re taking pre-orders now, and offer a discount if you sign up for a
subscription.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have fun :-)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Links to stuff:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.slackware.com/&quot;&gt;Slackware.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://store.slackware.com&quot;&gt;Slackware Store&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://mirrors.slackware.com/slackware/slackware-14.2/ChangeLog.txt&quot;&gt;x86&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://mirrors.slackware.com/slackware/slackware64-14.2/ChangeLog.txt&quot;&gt;x86_64&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jun 2016 12:52:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://exitstatusone.com/linux/2016/06/03/Slackware-14-2-released.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://exitstatusone.com/linux/2016/06/03/Slackware-14-2-released.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>Linux</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Back to Jekyll</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I wanted to switch back to Jekyll for quite some time now.  Using
AsciiDoc for my web site proved to be very low maintenance and required
very little effort to add new content.  I am going back to Jekyll
because I want to see how the project has progressed since I last used
it.  AsciiDoc is great but it is very boring to use!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I plan to use this version of the site as a blog.  I will post updates
or tutorials depending on what project I am working on, and what I think
may be of interest to others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will not be bringing back old site content from my previous jekyll
site.  There have been far too many advancements and changes with Jekyll
since I used that source code.  You can find the old source code on my
GitHub account If you are interested in looking it over.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/BrentonEarl/brentonearl.github.io&quot;&gt;My GitHub
Account&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 06 May 2016 08:40:23 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://exitstatusone.com/update/2016/05/06/Back-to-Jekyll.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://exitstatusone.com/update/2016/05/06/Back-to-Jekyll.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>update</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
