<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Gaming on devpaint</title>
    <link>http://www.ahri.net/categories/gaming/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Gaming on devpaint</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 05 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://www.ahri.net/categories/gaming/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>VVVVVV</title>
      <link>http://www.ahri.net/2013/10/vvvvvv/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.ahri.net/2013/10/vvvvvv/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h3 id=&#34;intro:edf0b1df9e2e226ec0c9379e5e49e937&#34;&gt;Intro&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.ahri.net/images/vvvvvv/map.png&#34; style=&#34;float:right; height:50%; width:50%; margin: 10px&#34; /&gt;

&lt;a href=&#34;http://thelettervsixtim.es/&#34;&gt;This is a game&lt;/a&gt; that&amp;rsquo;s taken minimalism as a
mantra; its aesthetic, audio, controls, and attitude as a whole push for a focus
on what you can do in the world, which is not huge but large and challenging
enough to provide a lot of enjoyment if puzzle and skill-based platforming
appeal to you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;pixel-art:edf0b1df9e2e226ec0c9379e5e49e937&#34;&gt;Pixel art&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first point point of judgement for me about any game is the graphics, and
these are retro; like really, really simple. This is taking pixel art right back
to Commodore 64 levels. I&amp;rsquo;m actually not a huge fan of the graphics; they&amp;rsquo;re so
utilitarian that there&amp;rsquo;s really very little artistry to the look; it&amp;rsquo;s no Fez!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the other hand the minimal graphics give the game a focused feel: you&amp;rsquo;re here
to solve puzzles and to die, it&amp;rsquo;s really clear and it fits with everything else,
and you really feel the charm of an unhappy face when you screw up &amp;ndash; it makes
me smile through the frustration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.ahri.net/images/vvvvvv/take_my_lead.png&#34; style=&#34;float:left; height:50%; width:50%; margin: 10px&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;chip-tunes:edf0b1df9e2e226ec0c9379e5e49e937&#34;&gt;Chip tunes&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The music, again, is simple but nicely paced to urge you on. The effects and
overall ambience has that minimalist feel but this time without feeling so raw;
more by design. I sat playing for a while with the game muted while taking
screenshots and it&amp;rsquo;s amazing what a huge difference in motivation is made by the
lack of sound whilst being challenged.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;cheap-controls:edf0b1df9e2e226ec0c9379e5e49e937&#34;&gt;Cheap controls&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The controls are simple too: left, right, invert, interact. And I debated
listing &amp;ldquo;interact&amp;rdquo; given that you need to hit enter only to teleport, read
stuff, or talk to other characters. You do none of these things frequently!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The controls are tight and you know that it&amp;rsquo;s your fault when you die, though
it&amp;rsquo;s a bit frustrating to hit spikes after the screen changes. To be fair this
is certainly by design, and there are rolling movement stages that really push
you to hit pace and ability in tandem which can be very rewarding.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;quick-death-cycle:edf0b1df9e2e226ec0c9379e5e49e937&#34;&gt;Quick death cycle&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a game like this you need to get back into the action after dying; much like
Super Meat Boy you pass the challenges through muscle memory as much as anything
else and being thrown back in encourages you to try &amp;ldquo;just one more time&amp;rdquo;. If I
were to &amp;ldquo;correct&amp;rdquo; one thing about the game it would be to remove the tiny delay
in re-spawn; this is the time that I decide to quit and removing it would change
that thought process; learn from SMB!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.ahri.net/images/vvvvvv/trinkets.png&#34; style=&#34;float:right; height:50%; width:50%; margin: 10px&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;puzzles:edf0b1df9e2e226ec0c9379e5e49e937&#34;&gt;Puzzles&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s important to distinguish between SMB&amp;rsquo;s purely skill-based gaming and
VVVVVV&amp;rsquo;s mix of puzzle elements and skill challenges; VVVVVV&amp;rsquo;s switched gravity
mechanic provides many slower puzzles that require a more Portal-esque mentality
to solve and progress, and its interesting companion subsection forces you to
consider the actions of an NPC, albeit in a form that you indirectly control.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;npc-interactions:edf0b1df9e2e226ec0c9379e5e49e937&#34;&gt;NPC interactions&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s almost not worth mentioning the NPC interactions; they&amp;rsquo;re so few and far
between. I&amp;rsquo;m calling them out simply because they make me smile: they really
embrace the general minimalism of the game by hinting at a back story but almost
mocking the idea that there&amp;rsquo;s any credible explanation for their predicament and
the context for our gaming. The sense of humour and its subtle, almost
dismissive character really appealed to me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;in-conclusion:edf0b1df9e2e226ec0c9379e5e49e937&#34;&gt;In conclusion&amp;hellip;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;VVVVVV is a cool indie game, great for a quick blast, it&amp;rsquo;s got a nice aesthetic
which some really nice tunes to keep the pace up and which really helps with
getting back into the puzzle you just failed, and fail you will!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>