<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
      <title>Development on Cognition </title>
      <generator uri="https://hugo.spf13.com">Hugo</generator>
    <link>http://cognition.ca/tags/development/index.xml/</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
    <copyright>Copyright Joshua McKenty.</copyright>
    <updated>Thu, 17 Sep 2015 20:13:09 AEST</updated>
    
    <item>
      <title>On Behalf Of</title>
      <link>http://cognition.ca/post/on-behalf-of/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Sep 2015 20:13:09 AEST</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://cognition.ca/post/on-behalf-of/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;The internet was invented by Vint Cerf.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But it was made usable by Marc Andreeson. And what he did was simple:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He turned it into a VCR.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, it seems deeply ironic to me that most of the folks reading this post have
probably never used a VCR, although they&amp;rsquo;ve most certainly used the Back, Forward,
Stop and Play buttons on a web browser.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was a powerful metaphor, and it made it possible for nearly half of the world&amp;rsquo;s
population to grapple with the experience of traversing a directed, cyclic graph.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And in much the same way that we floundered in the world of Gopher and Finger
protocols before Marc&amp;rsquo;s insight of metaphor, we&amp;rsquo;re floundering in the early world
of IoT.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We need a metaphor. And it needs to encapsulate a deceptively difficult concept:
 - Agency.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_0&#34;&gt;Understanding Agency&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My refrigerator may someday be able to detect when the cream has gone bad, and
order more - either from Amazon, or from some local grocery store delivery.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Quite literally, my fridge will be acting on my behalf - an agent, if you will.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It will authenticate itself with my home wifi network.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And again with the grocery service, with a payment provider, and possibly with
an independent shipping or delivery service.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Likely, though, the software that actually &lt;em&gt;orders&lt;/em&gt; the milk, won&amp;rsquo;t be running
on my fridge. Instead, it will be cloud-based, and acting &lt;em&gt;on behalf of&lt;/em&gt; my fridge,
which is in turn acting on behalf of myself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_1&#34;&gt;In Search of a Metaphor&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I was young, I worked as an apprentice carpenter. Often, this included errands
to the local hardware or lumber supply store. And usually, I was equipped for these
errands with my boss&amp;rsquo;s credit card (as well as his truck).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Strictly speaking, proffering someone else&amp;rsquo;s credit card (and signing for it) is
illegal, much the same as sharing the password or pin to your bank account. And yet,
the image of a household robot, with an empty milk jug in one mechanical hand and
a credit card in the other, is the best metaphor for delegated authentication that
I can come up with. And it&amp;rsquo;s simply not good enough.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>dotplan</title>
      <link>http://cognition.ca/post/dotplan/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2014 12:11:26 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://cognition.ca/post/dotplan/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_0&#34;&gt;Where in the world is Joshua McKenty?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;October 6: SF&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;October 13: Victoria&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;October 20: Korea and SF&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;October 27: Victoria&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;November 3: Paris and NYC&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;November 10: Victoria&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;November 17: LA and Denver&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;November 24: Victoria / SF&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;December 1: Arizona&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;December 8: Victoria&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;December 15: Toronto, NYC, SF&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;December 22: Victoria&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;December 29: SF&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Jan 5: Victoria&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Jan 12: DC, Atlanta, Kansas City&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Jan 19: Victoria, Vancouver&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Jan 26: SF, Detroit, Tampa,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Feb 2: Victoria, NYC&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Feb 9: Victoria, SF&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Feb 16: Victoria, SF&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Feb 23: DC, NYC, SF&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mar 2: Austin&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mar 9: Banff, DC, SF&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mar 16: Victoria, Vancouver&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mar 23: Victoria, Seattle&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mar 30: Victoria&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Apr 6: DC, Cincinnati, Seattle, SF&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Apr 13: Victoria, SF&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Apr 20: Victoria&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Apr 27: LA, SF&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;May 4: Victoria&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Liberty-Source</title>
      <link>http://cognition.ca/post/canada-source/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Sep 2014 19:54:09 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://cognition.ca/post/canada-source/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_0&#34;&gt;tldr: Use equity warrants for open source trademark licenses.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;toc_1&#34;&gt;Long Version:&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apache Software License v2.0 allows the free and unrestricted use, modification,
and what-have-you of the source code. However, it protects the use of the &lt;em&gt;name&lt;/em&gt;
and brand of an open source project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the OpenStack world, we license this brand to vendors who agree to follow a
trademark license agreement that includes, among other things:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Paying to be a corporate sponsor or member of the OpenStack Foundation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Using certain, unmodified sections of the open source code.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Passing a compatibility test suite for functionality of all public APIs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But we could have gone one step better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Imagine a trademark license where, along with cash and compatibility, the open
source entity also received a small amount of equity in the licensing firm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This would make the owner of the trademark, rather than being a non-profit
foundation, a Public Benefit Corporation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The stated public benefit purpose could guarantee that the source code license
and trademark policy would not be changed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And the equity stake would guarantee that this company would have the motivation
to improve and enhance the open source code to meet the needs of all the
licensees.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Keeping the core development teams &amp;ldquo;in-house&amp;rdquo;, so to speak.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While also being able to motivate these &amp;ldquo;best-and-brightest&amp;rdquo; through stock-options, and a potentially lucrative future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_2&#34;&gt;QUESTIONS:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Does this make the B-corp a &amp;ldquo;hedge fund&amp;rdquo; or some other entity?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Would the trademark license need to be baked into the bylaws of the b-corp for reasonable protection?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Could standard ISA stock options work for this?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_3&#34;&gt;FAQ&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Yes, this means I&amp;rsquo;m not a fan of the &amp;ldquo;everyone-contributes-and-scratches-their-own-itch&amp;rdquo; model of open source development. While I think that&amp;rsquo;s helpful for modules, plugins, and niche features, I think open source projects are best served by dedicated, core development teams. See Mozilla, Wordpress, Android, and Drupal for examples of this.

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Yes, this means that there can be a large community of &amp;ldquo;vendors&amp;rdquo; that are attacking the many go-to-market models which might logically exist for a single open source project. It&amp;rsquo;s like genetic algorithms - but for business. And the core open source organization benefits, regardless of which ones are successful.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>block chain</title>
      <link>http://cognition.ca/post/block-chain/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Aug 2014 22:01:58 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://cognition.ca/post/block-chain/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Trying to understand the ecosystem of &amp;ldquo;Proof of Luck&amp;rdquo; based distributed systems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.stellar.org/blog/introducing-stellar/&#34;&gt;https://www.stellar.org/blog/introducing-stellar/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Use observable phenomenon to time things:
 - &lt;a href=&#34;http://arxiv.org/abs/1311.3693&#34;&gt;http://arxiv.org/abs/1311.3693&lt;/a&gt;
 - &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pulsar#Precise_clocks&#34;&gt;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pulsar#Precise_clocks&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Use fancy algorithms:
 - &lt;a href=&#34;http://pagesperso-systeme.lip6.fr/Marc.Shapiro/papers/RR-6956.pdf&#34;&gt;http://pagesperso-systeme.lip6.fr/Marc.Shapiro/papers/RR-6956.pdf&lt;/a&gt;
 - &lt;a href=&#34;http://highscalability.com/blog/2010/12/23/paper-crdts-consistency-without-concurrency-control.html&#34;&gt;http://highscalability.com/blog/2010/12/23/paper-crdts-consistency-without-concurrency-control.html&lt;/a&gt;
 - &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.commsp.ee.ic.ac.uk/~mandic/dvv/papers/physica%20D.pdf&#34;&gt;http://www.commsp.ee.ic.ac.uk/~mandic/dvv/papers/physica%20D.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Dead Pool Pledge</title>
      <link>http://cognition.ca/post/dead-pool-pledge/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Aug 2014 01:10:41 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://cognition.ca/post/dead-pool-pledge/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;I love PaaS. Recently I&amp;rsquo;ve gone to great lengths to figure out a way to build
applications using ONLY SaaS and PaaS platforms. I managed this with a mix of
wercker, github, orchestrate.io and pivotal web services.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But with the commitment to any third-party platform, comes a certain kind of fear.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m a believer in open source. And I&amp;rsquo;m ALSO a believer in commercial software.
As much as I believe in the rights and freedoms of the user, I also value the
rights and freedoms of the developer - to license his or her work in the way that
they see fit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So here&amp;rsquo;s what I&amp;rsquo;m suggesting: a &amp;ldquo;Dead Pool Pledge&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Add &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/freepile&#34;&gt;this github account&lt;/a&gt; to your private repositories
as a collaborator. You can keep those accounts private, and your source code licensed under whatever terms
you feel is appropriate, as long as your business/project/coop is a going concern.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But the day that your company ends up in the Crunchbase deadpool, my bot will
republish your source code under ASLv2. Seem fair?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know that if Wercker, Orchestrate.io and others adopted this, I would sleep a
little better at night.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_0&#34;&gt;Caveats&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Okay, maybe we should try and contact you first - to find out if you&amp;rsquo;re attempting
to sell off those assets to a company who has a legitimate intent to continue
business operations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And yes, this whole thing probably ought to have some sort of contract in place -
maybe something that the SFLC or the EFF could draft up.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How I Learned to Stop Worrying and Love the (Static) Web</title>
      <link>http://cognition.ca/post/about-hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Aug 2014 19:22:29 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://cognition.ca/post/about-hugo/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m an early fan of the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.aaronsw.com/weblog/000404&#34;&gt;Baked, Not Fried &lt;/a&gt;
concept behind static web generators. But somehow, getting all the tools in place
to run one myself seemed onerous. A simple &lt;code&gt;apt-get install mysql&lt;/code&gt; was always
easier than the vaguely-mystical incantations required to get jekyll up and running.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then again, there was my deep-seated prejudice against Ruby. (See my previous
    trolling of the ruby community when I accused them of being singlehandedly
    responsible for Global Warming.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But with the emergence of &lt;a href=&#34;http://hugo.spf13.com&#34;&gt;Hugo&lt;/a&gt;, an elegant static site
generator written in #Golang, I&amp;rsquo;ve been able to get over the line. Or maybe it
was simply time that I had a blog again.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>