<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>devpaint</title>
    <link>http://www.ahri.net/</link>
    <description>Recent content on devpaint</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 30 Nov 2015 22:43:17 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://www.ahri.net/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>More painting</title>
      <link>http://www.ahri.net/2015/11/more-painting/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Nov 2015 22:43:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.ahri.net/2015/11/more-painting/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.ahri.net/images/painting/2015-11-30/1.jpg&#34; style=&#34;float:center; height:50%; width:50%; margin: 10px&#34; /&gt;

I&amp;rsquo;m trying my hardest to get back to using these dwarves as practice: they&amp;rsquo;re
supposed to be imperfect playgrounds with which I can learn some nice techniques
to use on my more impressive models.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.ahri.net/images/painting/2015-11-30/2.jpg&#34; style=&#34;float:center; height:50%; width:50%; margin: 10px&#34; /&gt;

I&amp;rsquo;ve managed to test out some weathering techniques along with using inks to
provide depth, before getting completely bored with this model and I&amp;rsquo;m fairly
happy with the results, even with the obvious mistakes and deficiencies in the
quality of my work.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shakey Hands</title>
      <link>http://www.ahri.net/2015/11/shakey-hands/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Nov 2015 21:24:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.ahri.net/2015/11/shakey-hands/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.ahri.net/images/painting/2015-11-23/1.jpg&#34; style=&#34;float:right; height:50%; width:50%; margin: 10px&#34; /&gt;

After a break of a few years I suddenly felt like painting again, mostly to calm
my mind and focus for a while. I&amp;rsquo;d forgotten quite how meditative it is!
Unfortunately I&amp;rsquo;m rather out of practise and lacking in confidence. I spent most
of my time considering how much impact that confidence has on my performance
across the board, making little mistakes here and there and dwelling on them
pointlessly. A microcosm of my psyche.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.ahri.net/images/painting/2015-11-23/2.jpg&#34; style=&#34;float:right; height:50%; width:50%; margin: 10px&#34; /&gt;

It&amp;rsquo;s clear how much of a waste of effort scrutinising those mistakes is, yet
it&amp;rsquo;s nigh-on impossible to push this behaviour away. After an hour or so I&amp;rsquo;d
decorated a shield, eventually letting the mistakes subside, and gaining
confidence to take broader, more clear strokes. I&amp;rsquo;d like to think I learnt
lessons from this but in reality, without that practise these revelations won&amp;rsquo;t
stick.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting into Containers</title>
      <link>http://www.ahri.net/2015/11/getting-into-containers/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.ahri.net/2015/11/getting-into-containers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For a while now I&amp;rsquo;ve been experimenting with &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.docker.com/&#34;&gt;Docker&lt;/a&gt;
which provides a useful level of abstraction over Containers. I&amp;rsquo;m still finding
my feet in this exciting new world of cheap sort-of-virtualisation but so far
I&amp;rsquo;m really enjoying the isolation they provide, allowing for explicit bundling
of dependencies and repeatable builds. You can probably see how interested I&amp;rsquo;ve
been from my &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/search?q=user%3Aahri+docker&#34;&gt;github history&lt;/a&gt;
these past months!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One thing I have found is that I don&amp;rsquo;t really trust other people&amp;rsquo;s builds all
that much and have been preferring to roll my own in most cases, which has the
benefit of forcing me to learn the tool but obviously contributes to the
existing problem that we already have lots of images purportedly doing the same
thing - just have a look at &lt;a href=&#34;https://hub.docker.com/search/?q=caddy&#34;&gt;the number of
images&lt;/a&gt; for
&lt;a href=&#34;https://caddyserver.com/&#34;&gt;Caddy&lt;/a&gt; to get idea of this problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The problem is two-fold: the first half is that builds are not necessarily
trustworthy because they aren&amp;rsquo;t signed - this is currently being addressed by
the Docker team. The second half is more subtle though; with the tech being so
new people are all doing their own thing in their own way; lots of images
require volumes mounting with configuration being provided that way, while
others prefer to take it from a central configuration provided by
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.consul.io/&#34;&gt;Consul&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;https://coreos.com/etcd/&#34;&gt;etcd&lt;/a&gt;. Personally
I&amp;rsquo;m erring towards stdin and command-line arguments where possible, largely
because I don&amp;rsquo;t like the volume solution and don&amp;rsquo;t have any experience with the
enterprise-level key-value stores.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Watching the trends and best-practises should prove very interesting indeed.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>So I got locked in a bookshop</title>
      <link>http://www.ahri.net/2014/08/so-i-got-locked-in-a-bookshop/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.ahri.net/2014/08/so-i-got-locked-in-a-bookshop/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;I began browsing the sci-fi section, looking for trashy stuff mostly, like Harry
Harrison. Having exhausted the obvious stuff I noticed a sign saying &amp;ldquo;more sci-fi
in the back!&amp;rdquo; so I obeyed the call and found big piles of sci-fi to trawl.
Heaven!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I should highlight at this point that this bookshop was described by my sister as
&amp;ldquo;the one that plays loud music out onto the street&amp;rdquo; and indeed it was blasting
out jazz this evening - a pleasant and quite endearing habit of theirs, but one
that turned out to be my downfall.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I continued to browse the books and amassed infinitely more in my I&amp;rsquo;ll-probably-
buy-this-stuff pile than I had expected (i.e. my expectation was for zero since
I already have plenty of unread books to plough through!) There&amp;rsquo;s some great
stuff there; from Harry Harrison to Heinlein to LeGuin, and even a Star Trek
book which I&amp;rsquo;m pretty dubious about, but hey it&amp;rsquo;s about Romulans so it&amp;rsquo;s gotta
be good, right?!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I eventually decided that the pile was big enough and that I should probably get
out before I bought half the shop.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I looked around. Nobody. Called &amp;ldquo;HELLO?!&amp;rdquo; a few times. Nothing. I analysed the
situation; the music was still on, as were the lights, there was an uneaten
salad of some variety prepped and ready to dig into. Cool. They must be around
somewhere.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I tried a couple of doors; one went downstairs and one up. It felt rather like
a mixture of a horror film and one of those old text-based adventures:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You reach the stairwell: do you want to go [U]p or [D]own?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I opted for Down: Up looked dark :(&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the basement there were a few things; a broken ladder, a couple of locked
toilets, and then more stuff, detritus mostly. Not worth listing in a
text-adventure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ok, so there&amp;rsquo;s nobody here. I&amp;rsquo;ll leave the hard-won pile of books near the till
and come back tomorrow. No big deal!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh shit. The door is locked. I&amp;rsquo;m stuck in someone else&amp;rsquo;s shop and I&amp;rsquo;m alone and
I have no food except someone else&amp;rsquo;s salad and when did I last use the toilet
and will I survive the night?!?! Perhaps panicking wasn&amp;rsquo;t going to be so
helpful: deep breath.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More investigation of the situation was needed: surely I was being a simpleton
and there was actually a way to open this locked door. Nope. Sealed. Not a yale
lock. Well then - let&amp;rsquo;s think logically about this - there must be spare keys?
Found precisely &lt;em&gt;one&lt;/em&gt; that looked promising. Didn&amp;rsquo;t fit. My heart sank.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ok, phone numbers then - there must be a mobile scribbled down somewhere! Rescue
is a phone call away! Nope. Ok, think laterally. Visit their website in search
of a number&amp;hellip; nope, only a landline for the shop&amp;hellip; try it anyway in the vain
hope that it&amp;rsquo;s forwarding.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;RING RING&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ok, that didn&amp;rsquo;t work. Tricky.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Around this time, and noting the security camera I decided it might be prudent
to call the police, hopefully demonstrating that I wasn&amp;rsquo;t involved in the heist
of a bookshop. I quickly got through, apologised in an extremely English manner
for wasting everyone&amp;rsquo;s time, and explained the situation, at which point I must
have been allocated the very lowest priority possible and stuck in a phone
queue being repeatedly informed that more important emergencies were going on
and to stop being a big baby. Well, that&amp;rsquo;s what I read into it anyway.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;know-your-enemy:fe40e36e17e5b65bbd1e8b9fb1c83adb&#34;&gt;Know your enemy&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Exploration was the way forward, it seemed, with no official attention (but
holding on for the police to pick up) I ventured forth. Up I went. More
shouting: &amp;ldquo;HELLO?! ANYONE THERE?!&amp;rdquo; thinking &amp;lt;I&amp;rsquo;m going to die&amp;gt;. Seems
overly dramatic, but read on! Coulda happened!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Floors of books, and knick-knacks, and less books as I went up: top floor was
largely empty - another ladder, not so broken looking, and jackpot! FIRE EXIT!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately the damn thing wouldn&amp;rsquo;t open - the push-bar thing was stuck and I
couldn&amp;rsquo;t urge it open, so I gave it a sharp kick and smelt the fresh air!
I felt like Mel Gibson leading the charge against the
melodramatically-and-largely-misrepresented English in Braveheart. FREEDOM!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Turns out it was open about 2 inches and now it was stuck. Really stuck. I
booted it a couple more times for good measure but it didn&amp;rsquo;t shift and I was
worried about breaking stuff. I decided to use the old lift-and-apply-pressure
technique. Cue sound of rotten wood giving way. Oops. Broke the top hinge. On
the plus side I could now get out, which I did, and then nipped back in and
down to the till to write a letter of apology.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hi&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You locked me in your shop! I tried calling you but couldn&amp;rsquo;t find your mobile.
I searched for a spare key to no avail.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I found a fire escape door at the top floor and pushed hard to open it, but
the wood was rotten and the top hinge broke! I&amp;rsquo;m sorry!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been trying to call the police for 20mins but they put my on hold so I&amp;rsquo;ll
try the fire escape.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll pop in tomorrow to buy the books! [arrow drawn here to the treasure-trove
of discovered books - my main concern at this point was genuinely that they
might re-file my treasure-trove!]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-Adam&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Back up I went, out onto the fire escape which I discovered was really rusty and
a lot higher up than I&amp;rsquo;d hoped&amp;hellip; I don&amp;rsquo;t really like heights! At this point the
police picked up and I apologised profusely and gave a short summary of events
culminating in my position at the top of a dodgy fire-escape, the door for which
I left ajar just in case I needed it - possibly the most sensible thing I&amp;rsquo;ve
ever done!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The nice bloke on the end of the line suggested that if I felt safe I should try
using the fire escape, and I didn&amp;rsquo;t want to seem too pathetic, having already
been locked in a shop by mistake, and gave it a whirl. The first step was solid
and I gained enough confidence to stride onto the next - which immediately
loosened and gave way on one side. This was a sobering moment indeed. Shit was
definitely real.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not willing to let such trivialities as death-by-fall-and-impaling get in the
way of a good escape I proceeded carefully down until I got to the first floor
which had had its escape ladder chained up and padlocked. The padlock looked
stronger than the entire set of stairs put together. I considered a heroic jump
to the floor but the nice man on the line suggested that this was perhaps not
the best idea.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He left me alone at that point for us both to regroup: he had to try to contact
the owners, and I had to re-climb the steps-of-little-integrity and wait for
rescue in the shop. It was out of my hands now - kinda reassuring in a pathetic
sort of way. I welcomed opportunity to use two hands now that I wasn&amp;rsquo;t holding
my phone and ascended, breaking bits off here and there and trying to retain my
sanity whilst considering my ridiculous death. Thankfully the door was still
open when I reached the top - I had already resigned to the inevitability that
it would&amp;rsquo;ve swung shut in the minimal wind so this was a positive development.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I resolved to wait, and have a read whilst I was there - may as well make use of
the perks available, right? After a few pages I got fed up waiting and called
the police back with my incident number and had a good laugh about my situation
with the very nice lady on the line - one should always appreciate one&amp;rsquo;s
ridiculous misfortunes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They had the foresight to enquire as to how much battery I had remaining: 33%
but I pointed out that I was manning the phones in the bookshop this evening so
if they needed me I was pretty available!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They had had no luck contacting the owner and were sending someone over.
Confused at what this someone might be able to achieve, and not welcoming the
spectacle of a fire-engine rescue, I went back to reading.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The police turned up and suggested that I could get back down the fire-escape
and they could bring a ladder, but by this point I&amp;rsquo;d decided a couple of things:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I wasn&amp;rsquo;t sure the fire escape would be charitable enough to stay up for a
redux&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This was going to take a while anyway, so why rush things?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We began discussing the fire brigade again and my heart sank. I could picture a
fireman triumphantly carrying me over his manly shoulder - the pathetic wretch
he supported not even able to escape a mere bookshop.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hey, this is my shop!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;God finally got bored of torturing me for cheap laughs. The owner was back!
One-and-a-half hours after leaving me to my doom. He&amp;rsquo;d gone for a coffee, and
this was the one time in 30 years running the shop that he hadn&amp;rsquo;t shouted &amp;ldquo;FIRE
DRILL! EVERYONE OUT!&amp;rdquo; before locking up. I was just relieved that not too much
fuss had been made, and was of course very apologetic about the door.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll be back tomorrow to buy that pile of books - they don&amp;rsquo;t take card, as it
turns out.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>uPubSub - A micro pub/sub implementation for NodeJS</title>
      <link>http://www.ahri.net/2014/08/upubsub---a-micro-pub/sub-implementation-for-nodejs/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.ahri.net/2014/08/upubsub---a-micro-pub/sub-implementation-for-nodejs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So I built my own PubSub&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;lt;dramatic pause, awaiting shouts of &amp;ldquo;Not Invented Here syndrome!&amp;rdquo;&amp;gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;heh. So I did this as a product of my need for an eventing system for one of my
secret side-projects, built using the CQRS and Event-Sourcing paradigms, for
which I needed a simple PubSub as my output. This grew slightly when I
implemented a simple Event Store and needed to latch onto all of the events that
pass through the system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my case I have no need of a topic-based approach or clever error-handling.
I&amp;rsquo;ve not even considered Promises and I don&amp;rsquo;t want to think about NodeJS vs.
Browser Compatibility. It&amp;rsquo;s all very interesting stuff but I need to stay
focused if I&amp;rsquo;m ever to finish what I&amp;rsquo;m doing, and of course if my requirements
evolve past the abilities of my simple little PubSub I&amp;rsquo;ll be more than happy to
swap to a 3rd-party library.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A whirlwind tour:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash line-numbers&#34;&gt;
$ npm install --save upubsub
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;then&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-javascript line-numbers&#34;&gt;
var uPubSub = require(&#39;upubsub&#39;),
    pubsub = new uPubSub();

function handler(message) {
  console.log(&#34;Handling &#34; + message);
}

pubsub.subscribe(&#34;eventName&#34;, handler);
pubsub.publish(&#34;eventName&#34;, &#34;foo&#34;); // outputs &#34;Handling foo&#34;
pubsub.unsubscribe(&#34;eventName&#34;, handler);
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For now I have a nice little pubsub that dispatches in an async manner, and does
as little clever stuff as possible. It&amp;rsquo;s available from my
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/ahri/upubsub&#34;&gt;github&lt;/a&gt; and
&lt;a href=&#34;http://npmjs.org/package/upubsub&#34;&gt;npm&lt;/a&gt; and weighs in at 66 loc and 1.72kb. If
you want to use it in a browser it&amp;rsquo;ll need to be run through
&lt;a href=&#34;http://browserify.org&#34;&gt;browserify&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One thing that did catch me out is that my app was built with a fluent interface
which doesn&amp;rsquo;t play nice when the output is events and the write-model is getting
updated later than the next fluent call. Oops. I could just force the pubsub to
be synchronous for testing purposes (the main use of the fluent API) but this
seems like cheating!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blogging Platforms</title>
      <link>http://www.ahri.net/2014/07/blogging-platforms/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.ahri.net/2014/07/blogging-platforms/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A pretty general title, but I&amp;rsquo;ve been putting some thought into it. It&amp;rsquo;s one of those projects I&amp;rsquo;d like to do at some point that isn&amp;rsquo;t now. I&amp;rsquo;ll call them &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ahri.net/categories.html#scribbles-ref&#34;&gt;scribbles&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what I&amp;rsquo;m thinking is that while I like editing in Vim, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t quite suit me as a blogging environment. To be clear I suppose that text editors don&amp;rsquo;t suit me as blogging environments and I&amp;rsquo;d prefer to see what I&amp;rsquo;m doing as I&amp;rsquo;m doing it. &lt;a href=&#34;http://ghost.org&#34;&gt;Ghost&lt;/a&gt; is pretty nice, but I haven&amp;rsquo;t put much time into understanding its way of doing things, and having gotten into &lt;a href=&#34;http://jekyllrb.com&#34;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt; and just pushing up to GitHub I think I&amp;rsquo;d miss the transparency of the approach.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;d like something that can mix up a few bits and pieces, and since I think in trees, here&amp;rsquo;s a sketch:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Markdown&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s nice, and I appreciate that it&amp;rsquo;s readable in text editors if that&amp;rsquo;s what I want&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Flat files&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Both the source and result should be flat so that hosting is easier&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Live Reload&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having that instant feedback helps to avoid mistakes, it&amp;rsquo;s pretty easy to achieve this these days, without nasty hooks into the browser&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Native code blocks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I want to be able to stick some code in and have it highlighted, and not need some other service, even though GitHub&amp;rsquo;s gists are cool&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A nice text editor that supports Vim key bindings&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because why would you want to type any other way? ;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I might code something up sometime, perhaps with a mixture of NodeJS, event sourcing and some other bits and pieces. Of course, it&amp;rsquo;s just as likely that I&amp;rsquo;ll end up getting used to using Vim &amp;amp; Jekyll as my environment and not waste any further time on it!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>When to stop caring?</title>
      <link>http://www.ahri.net/2014/02/when-to-stop-caring/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.ahri.net/2014/02/when-to-stop-caring/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I received some bad news about an estranged friend before I went on holiday and
my first reaction was really &amp;ldquo;should I even care?&amp;rdquo;, see; the estrangement was
pretty mutual and was the result of what I see as profound differences in our
respective approaches to friendship.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t want to dig all that up, having spent a long time getting to grips with
it and accepting that some relationships just don&amp;rsquo;t work. It really took a long
time to stop thinking about my friend and feeling hurt about what had happened.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So back on topic; I had this bad news and it stirred all these feelings up, and
my defensive reaction was simply that I shouldn&amp;rsquo;t care: so I&amp;rsquo;d try not to. I had
a good holiday but I did dwell on it in-between having fun: am I really being
honest with myself here? Can I really just ignore this bad thing that&amp;rsquo;s
happened? Let&amp;rsquo;s bear in mind here; the bad thing is completely not his fault so
it feels completely unjust to mix that up with the things for which I do hold
him accountable; those actions and inactions that led up to the split.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I haven&amp;rsquo;t managed to find an answer within myself to the question I&amp;rsquo;ve asked; I
can&amp;rsquo;t switch my feelings on and off, and I can&amp;rsquo;t stop caring or wanting to help
even if I (cynically) feel that I&amp;rsquo;ll end up disappointed that he&amp;rsquo;s not
magically become a friend I want to have. So I&amp;rsquo;ll help where I can and I&amp;rsquo;ll
hope anyway. I can&amp;rsquo;t see any other way that works for me.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Seinfeld Method</title>
      <link>http://www.ahri.net/2014/02/seinfeld-method/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.ahri.net/2014/02/seinfeld-method/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;It seems apt to start my new one-a-day blogging by discussing the &lt;a href=&#34;http://lifehacker.com/281626/jerry-seinfelds-productivity-secret&#34;&gt;Seinfeld Method&lt;/a&gt;
which has stood me in good stead for a number of different habits. But I&amp;rsquo;m
getting ahead of myself; I should explain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;motivation:e3b2d1aec77b4de4835daddcb4a91d04&#34;&gt;Motivation&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The idea is that you can wrest control of your habits away from your
subconscious - instead of being controlled by them. This means both creating
new habits and breaking those undesirable bits and pieces you have lodged in
your mind that you do without conscious thought.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;habits:e3b2d1aec77b4de4835daddcb4a91d04&#34;&gt;Habits&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what is a habit anyway? Wikipedia &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Habit&#34;&gt;says&lt;/a&gt;
&amp;ldquo;A habit (or wont) is a routine of behavior that is repeated regularly and
tends to occur unconsciously.&amp;rdquo; I think this is a helpful definition; it shows
off the strength that we can harness by taking control and using this artefact
of human psyche for our own, initially conscious, benefit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-gist:e3b2d1aec77b4de4835daddcb4a91d04&#34;&gt;The Gist&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So Seinfeld felt that just by doing something each day: making sure you really
&lt;em&gt;do&lt;/em&gt; it, you make it easier to keep doing it. He was applying it to writing
comedy, but I&amp;rsquo;m applying it in a few different areas: I used it to break my
habit of biting my nails, for example!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So how does it work? It&amp;rsquo;s pretty simple: you use a big, real life,
highly-visible calendar and mark off the days where you did, or didn&amp;rsquo;t do, the
thing you said you were going to do, or stop doing. Simple, right? The &amp;ldquo;chain&amp;rdquo;
part of it comes in where you don&amp;rsquo;t like to leave holes in your calendar - it
looks untidy - so you have this extra bit of motivation to execute the action
and cross off a day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;gotchas:e3b2d1aec77b4de4835daddcb4a91d04&#34;&gt;Gotchas&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I&amp;rsquo;ve used this method for a year or so and applied it in a number of ways
and found that you need to use a few guidelines in order to use it effectively.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Use vague objectives; don&amp;rsquo;t say &amp;ldquo;I want to go to the gym every day&amp;rdquo;, instead
say &amp;ldquo;I want to do exercise every day&amp;rdquo; &amp;ndash; this allows you to have a lazy day
now and then, or to do alternative exercise when you&amp;rsquo;re on holiday, i.e.
make sure that the goal is achievable each day.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Some goals require detail and that detail stops you doing them each day if
something comes up; e.g. I have some objectives around coding on a specific
project, where just doing miscellaneous coding wouldn&amp;rsquo;t do (because I like
neglecting projects&amp;hellip;) So you need to allow yourself &lt;em&gt;planned&lt;/em&gt; days off
where you know you won&amp;rsquo;t be able to do this activity.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I would say that needing to do this is a hint that you&amp;rsquo;re going too specific
   and should really be trying to back off and make the goal more manageable
   and flexible. So your preference should be to ease the goal instead of
   adding in a level of paperwork like this that could spell the failure of
   your objective.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Real-life, month-sized, single objective calendars are the way to go: you
might think that this will make managing many objectives difficult, and
you&amp;rsquo;d be right. Think of it as a hint that you shouldn&amp;rsquo;t push yourself so
hard! Physical calendars are really a must as they&amp;rsquo;re much harder to ignore
than some ephemeral digital version.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;when-am-i-done:e3b2d1aec77b4de4835daddcb4a91d04&#34;&gt;When am I done?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As with many things this is a judgement call: you&amp;rsquo;re done when you no longer
feel that executing your desired action takes any effort; you do that thing
naturally, without needing to make space for it in your schedule &amp;ndash; it&amp;rsquo;s now a
core part of your day. You can throw the calendar out and consider building or
breaking a new one.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VVVVVV</title>
      <link>http://www.ahri.net/2013/10/vvvvvv/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.ahri.net/2013/10/vvvvvv/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h3 id=&#34;intro:edf0b1df9e2e226ec0c9379e5e49e937&#34;&gt;Intro&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.ahri.net/images/vvvvvv/map.png&#34; style=&#34;float:right; height:50%; width:50%; margin: 10px&#34; /&gt;

&lt;a href=&#34;http://thelettervsixtim.es/&#34;&gt;This is a game&lt;/a&gt; that&amp;rsquo;s taken minimalism as a
mantra; its aesthetic, audio, controls, and attitude as a whole push for a focus
on what you can do in the world, which is not huge but large and challenging
enough to provide a lot of enjoyment if puzzle and skill-based platforming
appeal to you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;pixel-art:edf0b1df9e2e226ec0c9379e5e49e937&#34;&gt;Pixel art&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first point point of judgement for me about any game is the graphics, and
these are retro; like really, really simple. This is taking pixel art right back
to Commodore 64 levels. I&amp;rsquo;m actually not a huge fan of the graphics; they&amp;rsquo;re so
utilitarian that there&amp;rsquo;s really very little artistry to the look; it&amp;rsquo;s no Fez!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the other hand the minimal graphics give the game a focused feel: you&amp;rsquo;re here
to solve puzzles and to die, it&amp;rsquo;s really clear and it fits with everything else,
and you really feel the charm of an unhappy face when you screw up &amp;ndash; it makes
me smile through the frustration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.ahri.net/images/vvvvvv/take_my_lead.png&#34; style=&#34;float:left; height:50%; width:50%; margin: 10px&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;chip-tunes:edf0b1df9e2e226ec0c9379e5e49e937&#34;&gt;Chip tunes&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The music, again, is simple but nicely paced to urge you on. The effects and
overall ambience has that minimalist feel but this time without feeling so raw;
more by design. I sat playing for a while with the game muted while taking
screenshots and it&amp;rsquo;s amazing what a huge difference in motivation is made by the
lack of sound whilst being challenged.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;cheap-controls:edf0b1df9e2e226ec0c9379e5e49e937&#34;&gt;Cheap controls&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The controls are simple too: left, right, invert, interact. And I debated
listing &amp;ldquo;interact&amp;rdquo; given that you need to hit enter only to teleport, read
stuff, or talk to other characters. You do none of these things frequently!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The controls are tight and you know that it&amp;rsquo;s your fault when you die, though
it&amp;rsquo;s a bit frustrating to hit spikes after the screen changes. To be fair this
is certainly by design, and there are rolling movement stages that really push
you to hit pace and ability in tandem which can be very rewarding.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;quick-death-cycle:edf0b1df9e2e226ec0c9379e5e49e937&#34;&gt;Quick death cycle&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a game like this you need to get back into the action after dying; much like
Super Meat Boy you pass the challenges through muscle memory as much as anything
else and being thrown back in encourages you to try &amp;ldquo;just one more time&amp;rdquo;. If I
were to &amp;ldquo;correct&amp;rdquo; one thing about the game it would be to remove the tiny delay
in re-spawn; this is the time that I decide to quit and removing it would change
that thought process; learn from SMB!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.ahri.net/images/vvvvvv/trinkets.png&#34; style=&#34;float:right; height:50%; width:50%; margin: 10px&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;puzzles:edf0b1df9e2e226ec0c9379e5e49e937&#34;&gt;Puzzles&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s important to distinguish between SMB&amp;rsquo;s purely skill-based gaming and
VVVVVV&amp;rsquo;s mix of puzzle elements and skill challenges; VVVVVV&amp;rsquo;s switched gravity
mechanic provides many slower puzzles that require a more Portal-esque mentality
to solve and progress, and its interesting companion subsection forces you to
consider the actions of an NPC, albeit in a form that you indirectly control.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;npc-interactions:edf0b1df9e2e226ec0c9379e5e49e937&#34;&gt;NPC interactions&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s almost not worth mentioning the NPC interactions; they&amp;rsquo;re so few and far
between. I&amp;rsquo;m calling them out simply because they make me smile: they really
embrace the general minimalism of the game by hinting at a back story but almost
mocking the idea that there&amp;rsquo;s any credible explanation for their predicament and
the context for our gaming. The sense of humour and its subtle, almost
dismissive character really appealed to me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;in-conclusion:edf0b1df9e2e226ec0c9379e5e49e937&#34;&gt;In conclusion&amp;hellip;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;VVVVVV is a cool indie game, great for a quick blast, it&amp;rsquo;s got a nice aesthetic
which some really nice tunes to keep the pace up and which really helps with
getting back into the puzzle you just failed, and fail you will!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LibGDX on iOS!</title>
      <link>http://www.ahri.net/2013/09/libgdx-on-ios/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.ahri.net/2013/09/libgdx-on-ios/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The first &lt;a href=&#34;http://libgdx.badlogicgames.com/&#34;&gt;LibGDX&lt;/a&gt;/&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.robovm.org/&#34;&gt;RoboVM&lt;/a&gt; powered app is &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.badlogicgames.com/wordpress/?p=3193&#34;&gt;on the app store&lt;/a&gt;. This is really great news for indie game developers who don&amp;rsquo;t have the cash to shell out for &lt;a href=&#34;http://xamarin.com/&#34;&gt;Xamarian&lt;/a&gt; in order to deploy to iOS.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s a really exciting time for developers looking to write-once-deploy-everywhere as this enabled games written in Java using LibGDX to be deployed to the desktop, HTML5, Android and now (stable soon!) iOS.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TDD on Views</title>
      <link>http://www.ahri.net/2013/09/tdd-on-views/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.ahri.net/2013/09/tdd-on-views/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been struggling along for a while seeing whether I can bear the pain of employing Test Driven Development with my Views (I went for an MVC architecture for my app for simplicity) and I&amp;rsquo;ve gotten to the point where I&amp;rsquo;m just going to remove all the unit testing on them; it&amp;rsquo;s so brittle (as foreseen by everyone else).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The point of this post isn&amp;rsquo;t to express surprise, it&amp;rsquo;s to admit defeat and move on, perhaps revisiting UI testing when I have more time to properly dedicate myself to it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To be fair it really pushed me to create a decent architecture and did a great job of highlighting where my architectural decisions were poor, but it&amp;rsquo;s now feeling like cleaning it up would make rewriting my tests so arduous that I&amp;rsquo;m put off, and that should never be the case! Definitely time for them to die :)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>