<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Bibsonomy on P.F. Hawkins</title>
    <link>http://pfhawkins.com/tags/bibsonomy/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Bibsonomy on P.F. Hawkins</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 11 Aug 2008 11:38:10 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://pfhawkins.com/tags/bibsonomy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Stupid Simple Bibsonomy to Delicious Migration</title>
      <link>http://pfhawkins.com/2008/08/11/stupid-simple-bibsonomy-to-delicious-migration/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Aug 2008 11:38:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://pfhawkins.com/2008/08/11/stupid-simple-bibsonomy-to-delicious-migration/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A while back I switched from &lt;a href=&#34;http://delicious.com&#34;&gt;delicious&lt;/a&gt; to
&lt;a href=&#34;http://bibsonomy.org&#34;&gt;bibsonomy&lt;/a&gt; to handle all my social bookmarking needs. I
was all taken in by the RDF backing. I decided recently to switch back, since
it didn&amp;rsquo;t have the user base and general ecosystem, it&amp;rsquo;s geared toward more
academic pursuits, and RDF isn&amp;rsquo;t all it&amp;rsquo;s cracked up to be. Here&amp;rsquo;s a tarball
of the scripts I used to move the bookmarks back into delicious:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Download: &lt;a href=&#34;http://pfhawkins.com/bib2del.tgz&#34;&gt;bib2del&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Caveats:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;bibsonomy handles unicode characters, delicious doesn&amp;rsquo;t. I opted to delete/edit the few bibsonomy bookmarks that were giving me those errors, but it will error out when you pass delicious a title with a smart apostrophe, smart quotes, em-dash, or other non-ascii character.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It is a dumb script. It will take all your bibsonomy bookmarks and add them one by one, with a 1.1 second delay in between to keep delicious happy. If, for some reason, you pass delicious a unicode character and it errors out, it will attempt to readd all the bookmarks you successfully added the last go round.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You will need to ask bibsonomy nicely for a developer&amp;rsquo;s api key. delicious only needs username and password.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I could have written something that stored the bibsonomy bookmarks locally,
cleaned up the unicode, and then pushed everything to delicious, but this does
99% of what I wanted it to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;d like to give a shout-out to two fabulous webservices that allow RESTful
api access to the information they store on my behalf, and to those brave
souls who wrote python bindings to those apis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;P.S. Not only does delicious choke on unicode, but it stores tags as space-
delimited strings. Strings! Boggles the mind, it does.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>