<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Essay on P.F. Hawkins</title>
    <link>http://pfhawkins.com/categories/essay/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Essay on P.F. Hawkins</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 05 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://pfhawkins.com/categories/essay/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>On Hyperverses</title>
      <link>http://pfhawkins.com/2012/10/05/on-hyperverses/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://pfhawkins.com/2012/10/05/on-hyperverses/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m pretty sure that one of the reasons I never update this blog is
because I don&amp;rsquo;t &lt;em&gt;focus&lt;/em&gt; on any particular topic. Some people can dash
off unfocused blog posts at the drop of a hat. I, for good or ill, am
not a member of &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Set_theory&#34;&gt;that set&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Back in, oh, April-ish, I found a topic that not only I could obsess
over, but has proven to be an inspiration to write about online. I
started looking into Hypertext with a capital aitch, the idea that
writing with little interlinking bits would revolutionize literature
in unfathomable ways. It was a thing in the 90&amp;rsquo;s, right? Whatever
happened to that?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One thing led to another, and I started a steady diet of reading on
hypermedia APIs, hypertext, and electronic literature. And unlike
other such interests, I kept at it. This one hasn&amp;rsquo;t flagged beyond
reading a book or two. I am up to my armpits in instapaper articles
and PDFs (and I even purchased a couple trade paperbacks) that I not
only plan on reading some day, but am actually working on a reading
list to make sure I cover certain topics. Which sounds like a totally
normal thing to do, but it is far afield from my usual spotty reading
habits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Given the nature of the topic, I wanted not just to learn the topic,
but create within the constraints of the topic. And while octopress is
a fine blogging platform, I did not want to dash off a blog. I wanted
to craft a site. Which meant I&amp;rsquo;ve spent more time than I probably
ought to have diving into free font sites and learning CSS and Sass
and ultimately &lt;a href=&#34;http://middlemanapp.com&#34;&gt;Middleman&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And then I managed to squeak out what you see at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.hypervers.es&#34;&gt;Hyperverses&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While eventually (one of these days!) my coding chops will be almost
good enough to get across to the computer what my brain wants to do,
right now I generate a static site using Middleman. Which is classic
hypertext. It&amp;rsquo;s a step up from writing my own HTML, to be sure. But
it&amp;rsquo;s not as easy as blogging. I have to rewrite the site config every
time I build the site just to make sure the index page consists of the
new piece I&amp;rsquo;ve written. The CSS is atrocious, I bet the HTML is
nonstandard. There is a good deal wrong with this site. But.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since my focus is on hypertext, I wanted text to play a prominent role
in the design. I had designed a pretty decent typographic logo for a
header. It didn&amp;rsquo;t sit well. Finally I just ended up putting the site
name as a straight typed logo for the site. It still didn&amp;rsquo;t set well
on top, so I moved it and a lot of the boring site navigation stuff
down in the footer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The drawback to the approach I&amp;rsquo;ve taken is that while I&amp;rsquo;m happy with
how the design has turned out, the architecture behind the site is not
as &amp;ldquo;hypermedia&amp;rdquo; as I had originally envisioned. But at least now I
have a spot to write about it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I created &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.hypervers.es&#34;&gt;the site&lt;/a&gt; so I could spare the
less than tens of numbers of readers of this blog endless diatribes on
whatever literary or RESTful topic popped into my brain. Yet I did not
write. Partly because my personal life has been busy, but mostly
because I didn&amp;rsquo;t have a toolchain for the type of site I wanted to
build until I discovered Middleman. And even then, I&amp;rsquo;m not sure how
long middleman will be around. So it serves my purpose for now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Normally in the past if I&amp;rsquo;d encountered the obstacle of not being able
to write about the thing I really really wanted to write about right
then, I&amp;rsquo;d have given up. But instead I got my feet wet by creating a
twitter account, &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/hyperverses&#34;&gt;@hyperverses&lt;/a&gt;. And I
got hooked with that, doing research and finding new things to read
and occasionally making a point of my own.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The site only has one page. I will be adding more soon. The footer
almost certainly will be expanding in scope. I&amp;rsquo;ve started tagging the
pages within middleman but I have no idea if I&amp;rsquo;ll ever use the tags.
But it&amp;rsquo;s a start, and I&amp;rsquo;m excited.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Principle Regarding Ends And Means</title>
      <link>http://pfhawkins.com/2012/06/06/a-principle-regarding-ends-and-means/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://pfhawkins.com/2012/06/06/a-principle-regarding-ends-and-means/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Okay, listen up. This is pretty simple. I&amp;rsquo;m gonna start by defining terms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ends&lt;/em&gt; are goals. If you take action, you usually do so to accomplish an end. Say, if I go buy bread and deli meat, I do so in order to accomplish the end of eating a sandwich.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Means&lt;/em&gt; are the steps you go through to accomplish an end. So, in the sandwich example, purchasing bread and deli meat, putting a few slices of meat on the bread, getting a knife out and slathering one of the bread slices with mayo: all these are means to the end of ultimately eating the sandwich.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For some reason, people don&amp;rsquo;t realize all the implications of what I&amp;rsquo;m about to say:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It is never, NEVER okay to perform evil means in order to accomplish good ends!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;but-if-i-go-back-in-time-and-murder-hitler-i-could-save-so-many-jews&#34;&gt;But, If I Go Back In Time And Murder Hitler, I Could Save So Many Jews!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You just might save a bunch of Jews! Saving Jews is good. &lt;strong&gt;Murder is bad.&lt;/strong&gt; Guess what? &lt;em&gt;You can&amp;rsquo;t murder!&lt;/em&gt; Not without being evil, anyway. And you want to be good, not evil, for fairly obvious reasons I&amp;rsquo;m not going to go into here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;when-ought-i-apply-this-principle&#34;&gt;When Ought I Apply This Principle?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All. The. Time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Seriously. Any time someone suggests you do anything at all, or if you are considering any course of action, don&amp;rsquo;t just ask yourself &amp;ldquo;is my goal good?&amp;rdquo; Make sure you also ask yourself &amp;ldquo;are all the intermediary steps (that I can conceive of) that I need to take to accomplish my goal themselves good?&amp;rdquo; If even &lt;em&gt;one&lt;/em&gt; of those steps is just a &lt;em&gt;little&lt;/em&gt; evil, &lt;strong&gt;YOU NEED TO RETHINK THAT GOAL.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If your goal has an immoral mean somewhere, you can rethink it one of two ways:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;replace it with a moral mean&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;abandon that goal&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to be good, those are your only options.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;this-seems-hard&#34;&gt;This Seems Hard.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes! It&amp;rsquo;s very hard. If you actually try to live this out, you find yourself abandoning goals you would never in your most fevered imaginings dream you&amp;rsquo;d abandon. Giving up evil goals that seem like fun is hard enough; giving up legitimately &lt;em&gt;good&lt;/em&gt; goals is much harder. But it is completely and utterly worth it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Gamification of Storytelling</title>
      <link>http://pfhawkins.com/2012/01/25/the-gamification-of-storytelling/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://pfhawkins.com/2012/01/25/the-gamification-of-storytelling/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;IN WHICH&lt;/strong&gt; Story meets Technology, and they exchange Awkward Pleasantries&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I kept &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.usabilla.com/why-we-need-better-tools-to-tell-stories-with/&#34;&gt;this blog post about using technology to tell stories&lt;/a&gt; by Jurian Baas around because the underlying premise got under my skin. From the article:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;?the connectedness and interactive nature of the Internet can not only give us multimedia experiences, but also change the way we interact with text, our most basic manner of communicating after speech. I totally agree with Bret Victor on this: ?People currently think of text as information to be consumed. I want text to be an environment to think in?.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is insane.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Text &lt;strong&gt;is&lt;/strong&gt; an environment to think in. Oral storytelling &lt;strong&gt;is&lt;/strong&gt; an environment to think in. Stories don&amp;rsquo;t need to be reactive in order to be good stories. Text is not broken!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reading this piece, it seems that the approach that Baas wants to take is the &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gamification&#34;&gt;gamification&lt;/a&gt; of storytelling. Gamification at its essence is taking the techniques used in games to make whatever one is gamifying more engaging. The first example of experimental storytelling he gives is, unsurprisingly, an online game. (The other two examples, while they demonstrate the type of interactivity he is interested in, aren&amp;rsquo;t fully fledged stories.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While games are a fine medium in which to tell stories, the real tell that Baas is referring to gamification appears at the end, when he calls for the creation of more apps and frameworks to &amp;ldquo;create more compelling stories&amp;rdquo;. Here he confuses the medium with the message. There are plenty of terrible, non-interactive books that are just not compelling. There are a smaller number of books that, while just as non-interactive, are &lt;em&gt;extremely&lt;/em&gt; compelling. What makes some books compelling while the vast bulk languish in mediocrity?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The NARRATIVE! The story that is being told! A story could be interactive as all get-out, and not compelling. Heck, there are some books with prose as clear as meticulously polished crystal that bore the reader to tears with a limp tale.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What worries me about what Baas is advocating is, frankly, FarmVille. At its worst, gaming becomes non-compelling as a story, but extremely addictive as an activity. THIS is what gamification risks bringing to the table: tales full of empty interactions, devoid of story, signifying nothing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While I applaud anyone attempting to create a story in a new medium, never lose sight that the narrative, the story, is what drives &lt;em&gt;all&lt;/em&gt; mediums.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Fling With Mixel</title>
      <link>http://pfhawkins.com/2012/01/19/my-fling-with-mixel/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://pfhawkins.com/2012/01/19/my-fling-with-mixel/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;IN WHICH&lt;/strong&gt; Fingers Paint while Dry, and Egos are Lightly Battered in a Hollandaise Sauce&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;on-mixel&#34;&gt;On Mixel&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://mixel.cc&#34; title=&#34;Mixel&#34;&gt;Mixel&lt;/a&gt; confounds me as a piece of software that shines so brightly, the shadows of its flaws are made proportionately more apparent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://pfhawkins.com/images/mixel/yeti.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;A Yeti walks in the snowy woods&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mixel is an iPad app for making collages that has the whole &amp;ldquo;social networking&amp;rdquo; thing baked into its DNA.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Making a collage feels like something the iPad was &lt;em&gt;born&lt;/em&gt; to do. Swipe swipe, swipe swipe, tap, swipe, BOOM! ART! I am not an artist by training or temperament, although I do doodle extensively in the margins of my notebooks. Using a pile of raw ingredients and the few methods mixel provides for manipulating them, I can create something that, if it isn&amp;rsquo;t art, looks and feels like &amp;ldquo;art&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;on-art&#34;&gt;On Art&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://pfhawkins.com/images/mixel/jiminy-stardust.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;A silhouetted Jiminy Cricket umbrellas down over a bleak yet sparkly landscape&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The feeling of creating art is addicting, to an extent. In the first few weeks of use I found myself making mixels in the time I usually allot myself to attempt to write. I consider writing my usual art, and Mixel briefly supplanted it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the great things about collage is that pretty much anyone with scissors and someone else&amp;rsquo;s art can jump in. Mixel provides the scissors, pasteboard, and glue; the web provides the found art.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;art-is-communication&#34;&gt;Art is Communication&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://pfhawkins.com/images/mixel/birdswave.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;A wave crashes into the birds, as a saddened Awesomeface looks on&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At its most basic, art is a form of communication. The artist attempts to share anything from a stray thought to a full-blown series of experiences to the viewer of the art. As far as I can see (and I am no art theorist), the success of an artist might be judged in two ways: by the degree to which a piece of art succeeds in conveying its meaning to a viewer, and by the sheer number of people who view a piece of art.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When art is at its best, e.g. Michaelangelo&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;David&lt;/em&gt;, it is deeply evocative and widely-known. Art that is of high quality, but is not widely-known, is still a success. Art that is widely-known, but of low quality, I would call unsuccessful, as I would any art of low quality. Conveying its meaning is the ultimate purpose of art.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mixel, as an app, cannot directly focus on the quality of the art; that is the artist&amp;rsquo;s responsibility. What it &lt;em&gt;can&lt;/em&gt; (and does) do is get art out to the masses, both at creation and distribution. Mixel absolutely excels at this. From the creation standpoint, the choices the artist can make are limited, like any medium, but are not overly restrictive. It is easy to dive right in, and not too difficult to make more complex works.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From the distribution standpoint, Mixel uses an asynchronus follow system (think Twitter rather than Facebook). It has likes, and a limited amount of &amp;ldquo;loves&amp;rdquo;, or super-likes. Fairly standard social media fare.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The real innovation is in allowing anyone to remix any other mixel. When a mixel is viewed, it is shown with any other remixes of that mixel immediately following. If someone you follow loves a mixel, and you tap on it to get a better view, you will soon find yourself flipping through a remix thread, ogling the art therein. It is a completely natural (or perhaps completely human) way of serendipitously discovering new art and new artists to follow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;?If you could combine art-making with a dynamic social graph, then it can become addictive.? Khoi Vinh says in &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.macworld.com/article/163514/2011/11/mixel_lets_you_create_and_share_ipad_art.html&#34; title=&#34;Macworld review of Mixel&#34;&gt;this Macworld piece on Mixel&lt;/a&gt;. Part of me has trepidations about this sentiment. Addictions are bad, mmkay? And another qualm lurks in the background.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;on-identity&#34;&gt;On Identity&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://pfhawkins.com/images/mixel/planet-test-pattern.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Still Life with Test Pattern and Planets&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although I missed it when Mixel launched, there was a dustup right out of the gate with Mixel&amp;rsquo;s requirement that one use a Facebook account to log in. As far as external dependencies go, Facebook is a weighty one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.subtraction.com/2011/11/16/why-mixel-requires-facebook-login&#34;&gt;this post&lt;/a&gt; one week after launch, Vinh details why they chose Facebook for auth, as opposed to Twitter or rolling their own. While I would have attributed the choice to the fact that it&amp;rsquo;s easier to piggyback a social network off of the behemoth Facebook (e.g. as Spotify moved to for their signups), they really chose it because it practically requires someone to use their legal name. They want people to use their legal names in order to foster a certain type of sharing, a type that pseudonyms would, in their view, obscure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The best argument against this decision is in the comments thread of Vinh&amp;rsquo;s post: &amp;ldquo;You?ve created graffiti, but are keeping out Banksy.&amp;rdquo; Would Banksy be a worse community member of Mixel than if he wished to use his legal name? The second best argument, also in that thread, notes that &lt;a href=&#34;http://metafilter.com&#34; title=&#34;Metafilter&#34;&gt;Metafilter&lt;/a&gt; seems to get by just fine without requiring legal names. Metafilter made two decisions that foster the sharing and keep out the trolls: moderation and up front cost.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Metafilter employs several moderators who police the site for bad actors. Many sites do this. Even 4chan! And while Metafilter has superlative moderators, I don&amp;rsquo;t think that this is as big a factor as the $5 entry fee.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To be able to post and comment on Metafilter, you need to create a profile, which costs $5. That alone keeps the cost of trolling far higher than most trolls are willing to pay. This barrier to entry is a much more egalitarian barrier than requiring someone sign up for a third-party social networking service. It also has the added benefit of bringing in actual revenues. Right now, we are all creating mixels at the largesse of venture capitalists. Those VCs will want a return on their investment. I cannot envision a revenue scenario (aside from Mixel users actually paying for the app) that doesn&amp;rsquo;t drastically alter the &lt;em&gt;fantastic&lt;/em&gt; experience. Ads? Product placement? Make a Mixel with a coke bottle in it and be eligible for sweepstakes? Any of those would alter the type of sharing the app is currently creating far more than letting some people use pseudonyms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;art-is-communication-of-self&#34;&gt;Art is Communication of Self&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://pfhawkins.com/images/mixel/sanity-and-sensibility.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Mosaic ladies with phrenological facial features&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ultimately, how one chooses to communicate oneself is an intensely personal decision. Art is intensely personal. A name, or the forgoing thereof, is intensely personal. My disapproval of Mixel&amp;rsquo;s choice to require Facebook is also personal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Online, on &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/pfhawkins&#34;&gt;twitter&lt;/a&gt;, on this blog, just about everywhere, I present myself to the world as P. F. Hawkins. I don&amp;rsquo;t on Facebook, for two reasons. First, I use Facebook for friends I have met offline, and would know me by my given name. Second, Facebook won&amp;rsquo;t let me be P. F. Hawkins; I apparently have too many periods in my name. G. K. Chesterton, C. S. Lewis, and countless others from the past would not be able to use their most well-known names on Facebook.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;P. F. Hawkins is not a pseudonym. It is my real name. It is very easy for the public to tie it to my legal name. It is how I pursue and intend to pursue my primary art, writing. Mixel&amp;rsquo;s dependence on Facebook (and Facebook&amp;rsquo;s username choices, which Mixel has no control over) prevents me from presenting myself in this art form as the self I usually provide art as.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;to-sum-up&#34;&gt;To Sum Up&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mixel is a fantastic collage app. It really is! I enjoyed it thoroughly. But it has ceded so much control over the identity of its users to Facebook that it undermines its stated mission of bringing art to the masses. The masses use pseudonyms!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://pfhawkins.com/images/mixel/stop-making-mixels.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;David Byrne gives highly opinionted advice over a late eighties pastiche&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On Finding a Document Production Workflow for Emacs</title>
      <link>http://pfhawkins.com/2009/01/19/on-finding-a-document-production-workflow-for-emacs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2009 10:48:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://pfhawkins.com/2009/01/19/on-finding-a-document-production-workflow-for-emacs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have a modest goal: write some fiction. Instead of actually working toward
accomplishing that goal, I&amp;rsquo;m going to obsess about the toolchain and other
externalities used to support this endeavor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will use revision control. By an accident of history I will be using git.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will use a text editor. Since I don&amp;rsquo;t want to have to run into frictions
from modal editing while fiction writing, I will be using Emacs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If fictions were primarily distributed and displayed as &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.gutenberg.org/catalog/&#34;&gt;plain-text
files&lt;/a&gt;, I&amp;rsquo;d be good to go. They aren&amp;rsquo;t, and
I would like to at least attempt to send this higher up the food chain, ending
in either a Microsoft Word Document or PDF.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Say, LaTeX makes some nice pdfs. While it manifestly does not suck, and
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.gnu.org/software/auctex/&#34;&gt;AucTeX&lt;/a&gt; is the bee&amp;rsquo;s knees, I want to do
whatever I can in the way of premature optimization to tilt the ratio of
writing to formatting heavily in writing&amp;rsquo;s favor. LaTeX is formatting heavy,
so I&amp;rsquo;d like to avoid that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Docbook XML also suffers from the same issue. It is a well-specced and quite
nice document format. And while &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.emacswiki.org/emacs/NxmlMode&#34;&gt;nxml-
mode&lt;/a&gt; is bar-none the premier way to
edit straight XML, sorry, it ain&amp;rsquo;t happening.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, what essentially plain-text formats can I convert to either LaTeX or
Docbook XML, which I can then use to produce my output format of choice? As of
this writing, I see three viable options:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://orgmode.org/&#34;&gt;org-mode&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://mwolson.org/projects/EmacsMuse.html&#34;&gt;muse-mode&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://markdown.infogami.com/&#34;&gt;markdown&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://johnmacfarlane.net/pandoc/&#34;&gt;pandoc&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;org-mode ships with emacs, and is great. Writing novels in it would be
orthogonal to its original purpose in note-taking and agenda-organizing. It
only exports LaTeX/PDF, not Docbook. While it may work, I think successive
options are more promising.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;muse-mode is designed from the ground up for publishing, not note-taking. It
exports both LaTeX and Docbook. This would probably be my first choice, except
for one thing: its wiki syntax.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It seems asinine of me to start complaining about a wiki syntax now. I mean,
isn&amp;rsquo;t that the whole point of this exercise, to find a wiki-like syntax I can
convert from? Right. I&amp;rsquo;m not complaining about &lt;strong&gt;a&lt;/strong&gt; wiki syntax, I&amp;rsquo;m
complaining about &lt;strong&gt;this&lt;/strong&gt; wiki syntax. All in all it&amp;rsquo;s not necessarily a bad
one, but it is a domain-specific language for this mode only. &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.wired.com/monkeybites/2008/05/a-million-littl.html&#34;&gt;It enjoys no
reuse outside of this particular
application.&lt;/a&gt;
If the third option didn&amp;rsquo;t exist, I&amp;rsquo;d probably use it anyway.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But we have markdown, and the magical frobnicator that frobnicates markdown
into a potpourri of other formats: namely, pandoc. &lt;a href=&#34;http://jblevins.org/projects/markdown-mode/&#34;&gt;Markdown
mode&lt;/a&gt; is pretty handy, and I&amp;rsquo;ll
probably end up writing a simple minor-mode or git-hook bash script for
automating the pandoc conversions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll let you know how this turns out.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Undead</title>
      <link>http://pfhawkins.com/2008/09/02/undead/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Sep 2008 10:09:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://pfhawkins.com/2008/09/02/undead/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Un-&amp;rdquo; is a negative prefix denoting the opposite of the word to which it is
affixed. The nearest equivalent prefix is &amp;ldquo;non-&amp;rdquo;, which denotes the same
thing. &amp;ldquo;Un-&amp;rdquo;, however, also possesses a connotation (in many applications of
the prefix) of time, where previously the state or thing that is not, once
was.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the case of zombies, the term &amp;ldquo;undead&amp;rdquo; is used to refer to them as a
collective whole, as a race or species. &amp;ldquo;Nondead&amp;rdquo; is less appropriate, for
while it would convey the fact that zombies are far more ambulatory than the
normative deceased, it fails to convey that the zombies were once dead; or, if
it does convey that, it does so with much less force.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(Another example of this connotation, although one based in marketing rather
than in organic etymology, holds for &amp;ldquo;uncola&amp;rdquo;; 7up has always been a
carbonated sweet water, and therefore &lt;em&gt;a&lt;/em&gt; cola, although it subverts the usual
formulae for what is deemed as cola, and in so doing is perceived [due to
intensive advertising more than anything] as having progressed from a state of
being cola to a state of being &lt;strong&gt;beyond&lt;/strong&gt; cola.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The utility of the &amp;ldquo;un-&amp;rdquo; prefix used in this manner cannot be overstated. For
clearly, the undead, while no longer deceased, also are no longer living. The
simple addition of this prefix drums up a word for a third state of being.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book Lending</title>
      <link>http://pfhawkins.com/2008/08/30/book-lending/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Aug 2008 09:23:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://pfhawkins.com/2008/08/30/book-lending/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have a new theory of book-lending. I&amp;rsquo;ve always been extremely recalcitrant
to lend out my precious, precious tomes. They are my babies. Letting someone
else read them who certainly doesn&amp;rsquo;t appreciate them to the same degree, or in
the same kind, is a risky proposition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My current reading pile includes a heaping helping of &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Austrian_economics&#34;&gt;Austrian
Economics&lt;/a&gt;. I love this
stuff. A sense of economics on this scale rewires your brain circuitry (what a
crappy, ubiquitous brain-as-turing-machine metaphor) in subtle and not so
subtle ways. It is some of the best non-fiction reading I&amp;rsquo;ve engaged in in
years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have to lend these books out. I simply must. I&amp;rsquo;ve attempted to get others
interested in them, with a little success. My brother, who is reliabel in
returning books I&amp;rsquo;ve lent him unread, raved about Ron Paul&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/redirect.html?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;location=http%3A%2
F%2Fwww.amazon.com%2FRevolution-Manifesto-Ron-Paul%2Fdp%2F0446537519%3Fie%3DUT
F8%26s%3Dbooks%26qid%3D1220101874%26sr%3D8-1&amp;amp;tag=phawkcom-20&amp;amp;linkCode=ur2&amp;amp;camp
=1789&amp;amp;creative=9325&#34;&gt;The Revolution:
A Manifesto&lt;/a&gt;, which got me started on this kick. I&amp;rsquo;ll next lend him
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/redirect.html?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;locat
ion=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.amazon.com%2FEconomics-One-Lesson-Shortest-Understand%2Fd
p%2F0517548232%3Fie%3DUTF8%26s%3Dbooks%26qid%3D1220102088%26sr%3D8-1&amp;amp;tag=phawk
com-20&amp;amp;linkCode=ur2&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=9325&#34;&gt;Economics in One Lesson&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Henry_Hazlitt&#34;&gt;Henry
Hazlitt&lt;/a&gt;. And I&amp;rsquo;ve gotten better
about lending out other sacred cows; after the Watchmen trailer hit the web I
lent &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/redirect.html?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;location=http%3A
%2F%2Fwww.amazon.com%2FWatchmen-Alan-Moore%2Fdp%2F0930289234%3Fie%3DUTF8%26s%3
Dbooks%26qid%3D1220102292%26sr%3D8-1&amp;amp;tag=phawkcom-20&amp;amp;linkCode=ur2&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;cr
eative=9325&#34;&gt;my copy&lt;/a&gt; to a friend at work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The realization, which has been slow in coming, dawns that I&amp;rsquo;ve read book X
once, and the odds of me rereading it in the next few years are pretty slim. I
can, therefore, safely risk the copy into the hand of others, where they can
better and more frequently fulfill their functions as books. A book is at its
best when its being read, when a man is bending his soul to the shape of
another&amp;rsquo;s thought. The more capital I can pump into the marketplace of
thought, the better served the consumers of that capital; not humanity, but
flesh-and-blood humans. I&amp;rsquo;ve a couple books, mostly reference, that others can
read only in the confines of my abode, but they are now the exception rather
than the rule.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Frittering</title>
      <link>http://pfhawkins.com/2008/08/20/frittering/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Aug 2008 09:32:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://pfhawkins.com/2008/08/20/frittering/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I fritter away a lot of time. This bothers. I have a stack or two of notecards
I ostensibly use to keep track of what I should be doing in my sparer time.
It&amp;rsquo;s been a week since I used them. I instead allow urgent or interesting
tasks to fill my time. I don&amp;rsquo;t exert my will over this time like I ought.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t wonder that &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/redirect.html?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;locat
ion=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.amazon.com%2FGetting-Things-Done-Stress-Free-Productivity
%2Fdp%2F0142000280%3Fie%3DUTF8%26s%3Dbooks%26qid%3D1219350056%26sr%3D8-1&amp;amp;tag=p
hawkcom-20&amp;amp;linkCode=ur2&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=9325&#34;&gt;GTD&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.assoc-
amazon.com/e/ir?t=phawkcom-20&amp;amp;l=ur2&amp;amp;o=1&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt; is so popular online. It really is
the ultimate self-help cottage industry. Promises of satisfaction for engaging
in bite-sized tasks with Pavlovian-addicting rewards (productivity!) and a
requirement for some physical products (book, labler, etc.) add up to a
healthy economic niche.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I spent 45 minutes watching foxtrot and tango videos on youtube yesterday.
This wasn&amp;rsquo;t nearly as mch fun as the ballroom dance classes I recently
completed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have, in my stack of notecards, a couple tasks that cannot be broken down
into any further smaller, more manageable chunks. They start with words like
&amp;ldquo;Research&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Draft&amp;rdquo;. I usually just work on the ones starting with &amp;ldquo;call&amp;rdquo;,
&amp;ldquo;reply&amp;rdquo;, and &amp;ldquo;check&amp;rdquo; instead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If I had an accurate brand, my logo would be of a slowly-leaking tire, doing
most things right, but heading for reinflation or replacement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I fear the most worthwhile thing I&amp;rsquo;ve been doing in my spare time is rereading
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/redirect.html?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;location=http%3A%2F
%2Fwww.amazon.com%2FJane-Eyre-Norton-Critical-Editions%2Fdp%2F0393975428%3Fie%
3DUTF8%26s%3Dbooks%26qid%3D1219238761%26sr%3D8-7&amp;amp;tag=phawkcom-20&amp;amp;linkCode=ur2&amp;amp;
camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=9325&#34;&gt;Jane Eyre&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.assoc-
amazon.com/e/ir?t=phawkcom-20&amp;amp;l=ur2&amp;amp;o=1&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Some Thoughts on The Dark Knight</title>
      <link>http://pfhawkins.com/2008/07/28/some-thoughts-on-the-dark-knight/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Jul 2008 17:38:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://pfhawkins.com/2008/07/28/some-thoughts-on-the-dark-knight/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I went and saw the Dark Knight again. This time I went with my parents. My mom
is a pretty devout woman with a decent artistic sensibility. Afterward she was
still trying to process the experience, and it was good to get her take on
things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One thing she said that struck me: &amp;ldquo;Everyone says it&amp;rsquo;s lots darker than Batman
Begins. I hate that. It&amp;rsquo;s not dark, it&amp;rsquo;s sadistic.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In one sense, she&amp;rsquo;s right. It is sadistic. But the sense in which she&amp;rsquo;s right
is incomplete. The &lt;em&gt;Joker&lt;/em&gt; is sadistic, not the film. He is a twisted sadist
whose mere presence should have given the film an R rating. But the film
doesn&amp;rsquo;t glorify that evil, it &lt;em&gt;exposes&lt;/em&gt; it. It presents a glimmer of hope and
a dash of martyrdom in the face of such evil.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And what evil it is. The Joker embodies depravity detached from sanity and
given free reign to deconstruct everything and everyone around him. And by
deconstruct, I mean either blow up or bring to despair.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My mom had another point: &amp;ldquo;Won&amp;rsquo;t portraying that evil push some people over
the edge?&amp;rdquo; Perhaps, but it is their choice to follow the siren song of evil.
The film is structured in such a way to make it clear that there are many and
profound negative consequences for allowing yourself to embrace that evil.
Two-face dies, spiritually in his rampage and then actually. Batman, by way of
contrast, has long ago learned to live with his grief and not succumb to the
temptations of despair. The contrast clearly highlights that the evil is not
to be trusted or embraced. Good clearly triumphs, to the extent that it can
given the horrific, 9-11 scale circumstances.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m considering catching a third screening, partly to let it sink in one more
time, and partly to see it in IMAX. And in choosing whether to, I do need to
take some of my mother&amp;rsquo;s concerns into account. Art does affect us,
powerfully, deeply, and there is a legitimate risk of responding improperly to
art. And such art should play only a minimal role in our lives. One of my
criticisms of the character of Father Ruiz-Sanchez in &lt;a href=&#34;h
ttp://www.amazon.com/gp/redirect.html?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;location=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.amazon
.com%2FCase-Conscience-Del-Rey-Impact%2Fdp%2F0345438353%3Fie%3DUTF8%26s%3Dbook
s%26qid%3D1217280480%26sr%3D8-1&amp;amp;tag=phawkcom-20&amp;amp;linkCode=ur2&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creativ
e=9325&#34;&gt;A Case of Conscience&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.assoc-amazon.com/e/ir?t=phawkcom-20&amp;amp;l=ur2&amp;amp;o=1&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt; is that
he didn&amp;rsquo;t read scripture or the divine office nearly as much as he read
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/redirect.html?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;location=http
%3A%2F%2Fwww.amazon.com%2FFinnegans-Wake-Penguin-Modern-Classics%2Fdp%2F014118
311X%3Fie%3DUTF8%26s%3Dbooks%26qid%3D1217280878%26sr%3D8-1&amp;amp;tag=phawkcom-20&amp;amp;lin
kCode=ur2&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=9325&#34;&gt;Finnegan&amp;rsquo;s Wake&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.assoc-
amazon.com/e/ir?t=phawkcom-20&amp;amp;l=ur2&amp;amp;o=1&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;. Art was taking up an unhealthy chunk
of his life, likely because he gave himself over to some aspects of the work
that he responded wrongly to. But the work &lt;em&gt;as a whole&lt;/em&gt; needs to be
considered, not just the villain. And you can&amp;rsquo;t allow a work of art to push
you over the edge.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blogging is Not a Science</title>
      <link>http://pfhawkins.com/2008/05/19/blogging-is-not-a-science/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2008 10:50:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://pfhawkins.com/2008/05/19/blogging-is-not-a-science/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There is something about data that recommends itself. The more data you have
the more you ostensibly know about the subject; the more you know the better
basis you have for your decisions; the better foundation for your decisions
the higher the odds your decisions are the right ones. Everyone likes to make
the right decisions. Few things are as truly satisfying.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That said, most data are crap. If they&amp;rsquo;re not inaccurate then they draw your
focus to teh wrong thing. Instead of basing your decisions on what it is
you&amp;rsquo;re actually doing, you&amp;rsquo;re basing them on a reading of the effects they had
the last time you did them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The above is exemplified in web statistics. Say, for example, that you start
blogging. You&amp;rsquo;re shouting into the void on a regular basis, and then BAM!
&lt;a href=&#34;http://sachachua.com/wp/2007/10/12/how-i-came-to-love-emacs/&#34;&gt;someone links&lt;/a&gt;
to &lt;a href=&#34;http://pfhawkins.com/2007/10/10/how-i-came-to-love-
emacs/&#34;&gt;one of your pieces&lt;/a&gt;, and you watch your stats shoot up. The tempting thing to do is write
a &lt;a href=&#34;http://pfhawkins.com/2007/10/15/how-i-use-emacs/&#34;&gt;similar piece&lt;/a&gt; on the
same topic. AND YOU WOULD BE WRONG.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What worked the first time? Writing something you wanted to write for the sake
of writing it. The second time, your ulterior, utilitarian motives will work
against you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was spurred to write this by &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/al3x/statuses/812166550&#34;&gt;this
tweet&lt;/a&gt;, with which I completely
agree. On the one hand, blogging is a conversation. On the other, it is
shouting into the void. There are no guarantees that anyone will click your
way, or read what you&amp;rsquo;ve written once they get there. And if &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ronaldlewis/statuses/310321802&#34;&gt;that&amp;rsquo;s your
focus&lt;/a&gt;, well, maybe you&amp;rsquo;ll
get the links, but you&amp;rsquo;ll have sold out. I&amp;rsquo;m not condemning selling out, it
has its time and place, but there is a reason people sneer when they say &amp;ldquo;he
sold out&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m putting my money where my mouth is: goodbye Google Analytics. Goodbye
data. If you need me, &lt;a href=&#34;http://pfhawkins.com/contact/&#34;&gt;email works best&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thoughts Writers Have</title>
      <link>http://pfhawkins.com/2008/05/11/thoughts-writers-have/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 May 2008 03:53:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://pfhawkins.com/2008/05/11/thoughts-writers-have/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I could really go for a smoke. I&amp;rsquo;m a non-smoker. The most I ever smoked was
three times in one kinda stressful week in college. And I try to buy the good
stuff when I do. No Camels for me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If I ever want a smoke, it&amp;rsquo;s because I&amp;rsquo;ve an itch that needs scratching, and a
cigarette seems like the shortest path to itch relief. It never is though.
There&amp;rsquo;s a deeper underlying reason why I have dry skin. The itching won&amp;rsquo;t
abate until I eat my vitamins, or eat animal fats, or stop eating melons, or
get new genes. The rest is vapid style.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s so much style to smoking. Nowadays it happens outside. Always with the
lighting it, holding it in your fingers, sucking on it, occasionally looking
at it. It&amp;rsquo;s the perfect excuse to take a break, because who would deny an
itching man his scratch? And it can&amp;rsquo;t be done indoors. So it becomes a
paradigm shift. An opportunity for a moment. With friends, huddled against the
cold and the itch. Or alone with the itch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s that kind of moment, and then there&amp;rsquo;s mortal peril. That innocent
girl, tied against the tracks, kicking her petticoat. The mustachioed man
behind the bushes, twirling his handlebar with growing glee as his dastardly
design is about to bear fruit. And our clean, upright protagonist, whose white
teeth shine brightly in his favor as he strains against inconceivable odds to
ride his worthy steed to the rails in time to throw the switch, sending the
train on a different path, the one without a buxom beauty. The thrall of
potential defeat in the moments before improbable success.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Catharsis. You can relax now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In those moments, either smoking or rescuing a blossom of virginity from the
jaws of death, in these moments are birthed a potential writer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is no such thing as a Greek muse, but there is such a thing as a moment.
Live through enough successive ones with a tolerably observant eye, and one
will feel, think, experience. And that will either need to be processed or
dismissed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Writing about it can scratch that itch. But the root cause will be here until
judgment day.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Allen Ginsberg vs. the Internet</title>
      <link>http://pfhawkins.com/2008/03/08/allen-ginsberg-vs-the-internet/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Mar 2008 00:48:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://pfhawkins.com/2008/03/08/allen-ginsberg-vs-the-internet/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Allen Ginsberg sang the slow poetry of the technological age before its time.
He took the time to wallow in the horrors of the banal that flit by us as fast
as we can click thru. With Whitman as his muse, he turned our eyes from nature
to our fractured nature, and held our gaze.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t even especially like Ginsberg&amp;rsquo;s poetry. Give me Hopkins any day. But
the torrent of measured fitfulness poured out as a fruitless libation, sterile
poetry stank with death, demise, burrowing in little rat holes for faint hope;
well there&amp;rsquo;s more &lt;em&gt;there&lt;/em&gt; there than the internet, right? A goodly bit of the
tubes piping bare flesh into bare hands and barren hearts, the rest amalgams
of news, quizzes, pokes, wanton squealing over shiny things, and poor people
mortgaging themselves on the next turn-key SEO keyword whitepaper build an
audience dropship four hour solution (run on index cards, of all things). Well
of course Ginsberg&amp;rsquo;s deadbeat doped out strung hipster buds and their very
real suffering has more life than that. Life takes time. Poetry takes time.
The tubes steal attention, the grist of living. Time bandits. Attention
pirates. Design masquerading as art. The shocking parading as feeling. This
pause pretending to be an ending.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How I Use Emacs</title>
      <link>http://pfhawkins.com/2007/10/15/how-i-use-emacs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Oct 2007 16:17:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://pfhawkins.com/2007/10/15/how-i-use-emacs/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;When I started using Emacs, I had grandiose notions of producing copious
amounts of prose, linking it together in all sorts of interesting and helpful
ways, and basically revolutionizing the way I experienced computers. But most
of all, I had a new and urgent desire to do everything from the keyboard in a
blazingly efficient manner.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I proceeded to burn the Emacs keybindings into my brain and fingers. I
developed some slightly inefficient workflows (copying and pasting from text
documents into OpenOffice documents, editing the original text file based on
whatever page length I was going for, rinse and repeat until paper is
produced) that were, on the whole, a net gain due to the speed of typing
without mousing. The linux filesystem positively danced under my fingertips. I
had more control over my system than I had ever had on Windows.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I progressed to producing documents and drafts in LaTeX. While it&amp;rsquo;s a bit
arcane, using Emacs with AUCTeX made writing LaTeX arguably faster (and
certainly prettier) than writing in Microsoft Word. My long-held desire,
though, was to &lt;em&gt;learn a programming language&lt;/em&gt; (I chose python) and &lt;em&gt;code my
own Content Management System&lt;/em&gt;. Events in meatspace have conspired against me
acheiving that goal up to this point; now I am making progress. I can&amp;rsquo;t
imagine working in any other editor. Oh wait: I can. I switched to vim for
four months earlier this year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;yes-i-tried-vim&#34;&gt;Yes, I tried Vim&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You heard me: I tried vim. My main motivation was a bout of Emacs Pinky. My
left pinky occasionally gets sore if I spend too much time on the laptop. At
the time I attributed it to the control sequences that Emacs uses, but now I&amp;rsquo;m
more aware that it&amp;rsquo;s just that my laptop has an inelegant and potentially
harmful keyboard. If I use an ergonomic keyboard with Emacs, I&amp;rsquo;m fine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Vim was fine. It&amp;rsquo;s a great text editor. If you want a powerful text editor,
your two choices are vim and Emacs, and though I prefer Emacs, I won&amp;rsquo;t fault
you for choosing vim. It does some fantabulous things. You can script it in
python, for example. But scripting vim in python feels a &lt;strong&gt;lot&lt;/strong&gt; like
scripting Emacs in python; there&amp;rsquo;s a lot of cruft, and it doesn&amp;rsquo;t play well
with the innards of the system like elisp does. And there were all these
little things that I missed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;what-i-m-doing-with-emacs-now&#34;&gt;What I&amp;rsquo;m Doing With Emacs Now&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m evolving into the type of person who tries to do as much as possible
inside Emacs. Here&amp;rsquo;s a partial list of how I use it now:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Email client&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Personal Planner&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Coding environment for my as-yet-unfinished CMS&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Twitter&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Writing Fiction&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;irc&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;limited web browsing (mostly online APIs for the python libraries I&amp;rsquo;m investigating)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;World Domination
Okay, I really haven&amp;rsquo;t used Emacs for world domination yet. But as I was
reading &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0812579844?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;t
ag=phawkcom-20&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=9325&amp;amp;creativeASIN=0812579844&#34;&gt;The Golden Age&lt;/a&gt;,
I was slightly disappointed when he was naming some of the far-future self-
aware AI characters, and Emacs didn&amp;rsquo;t make the list.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How I Came to Love Emacs</title>
      <link>http://pfhawkins.com/2007/10/10/how-i-came-to-love-emacs/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Oct 2007 11:25:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://pfhawkins.com/2007/10/10/how-i-came-to-love-emacs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is the story of a man and his favorite text editor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 2001, I was a freshman in college, which meant the closest thing to
highspeed internet that I had hitherto experienced. Which upped my time
surfing the web. One of the delightful sites I lighted upon was
&lt;a href=&#34;http://ftrain.com&#34;&gt;Ftrain.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One day, I dug through Ftrain&amp;rsquo;s archives and found &lt;a href=&#34;http://ftrain.com/util_emacs_hints.html&#34;&gt;Emacs
Notepad&lt;/a&gt;. I was intrigued. Having
exclusively used Word (and Notepad to edit HTML - ha!) up until that point,
this Emacs thingy sounded fascinating. I downloaded a Windows version right
away.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I soon found that the Windows port of Emacs was stuck on version 19, and the
rest of the Emacs-lovin&amp;rsquo; universe was using version 21 on some posix-compliant
operating system. I decided to hope and pray that soon the Emacs developers
would take a little time out to help us poor souls using Windows.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was a long wait. A long wait in which &lt;em&gt;I could not get LaTeX to work&lt;/em&gt;. So
long, in fact, that the next fall, with the aid of a new dorm-mate, I dual-
booted Red Hat 9 Linux.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s great about Emacs, and about free software in general, is that I have
as much control as I desire over my computer. I haven&amp;rsquo;t taken the time to
install Linux from scratch, but if I wanted to, the tools are there, and there
aren&amp;rsquo;t any proprietary hindrances or DRM snafus to thwart my progress. My
limited ability to understand maths may hinder me, but my software isn&amp;rsquo;t.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So actually, I am indebted to Emacs for not only making my computing life much
easier and more productive, but from freeing me from the limitations of
Microsoft. Although I see I didn&amp;rsquo;t really describe just how it has made my
computing life easier, or more productive. I&amp;rsquo;ll have to remedy that in a
future post.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;DISCLAIMER: I never said it was a good story of a man and his favorite text
editor.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>